[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
Okay, so let's take these ratings that we were just talking about.
好的 让我们看看刚才讨论的评分矩阵
And instead of talking about them for a specific combination of a movie and
现在我们不再讨论如何将电影和用户以某种方式结合起来
a user, let's talk about how we can think about representing our predictions over
而是探讨如何做出推测
the entire set of users and movies.
基于完整的用户和电影数据进行的推测
And to do this, we're gonna need a little bit of linear algebra.
这里 将需要一些线性代数的知识
So in particular, if we're looking at the score that we're giving
特别是 当我们推测用户u对于特定电影v会给出的评价时
So this is rating [BLANK AUDIO]
那么 这就是评价rating [写字声]
predicted for user u and movie v.
对于用户u对电影v的假设评价
Well, what did we say that was?
那么 按我们之前所说 这表示什么呢？
We said we took the user vector Lu, and we took the movie vector Rv,
我们说过 我们获得了用户向量Lu 和电影向量Rv
and we did this element-wise product, and
并且将它们按元素相乘
summed over the elements of that product.
然后将乘积按元素相加求和
So I'm gonna denote that just with this little notation here.
接下来我会用 小括号 来指代这个过程
So these little braces here mean we're gonna take the vector Lu and
这里的小括号表示我们将对向量Lu和
the vector Rv, do an element-wise product, and sum.
向量Rv 进行按元素的相乘 然后相加求和
Okay, so what that represents is we're taking a row
好的 那么这表示的是 我们将取出大矩阵 L 中的一行
of a big matrix L, so there's a row that has a vector Lu.
这行就是向量Lu
So let me write this a little bit more largely here,
这里我将这个写的更大些
so this row Lu is the vector that we talked about before.
这一行Lu就是我们前面讨论的向量
With how much that user likes different things like action,
表示用户对不同类型电影 (比如动作片 爱情片 之类)的喜欢程度
romance, and so on, and
表示对于用户对不同类型电影 (比如动作片 爱情片 之类)的喜欢程度
then we take a movie vector, Rv.
然后 对于电影向量 Rv
So again, we'll write it more largely here.
这里我再把它写的大些
So Rv is indexed over the same set of genres, or
Rv 是关于电影相同的类型或主题集合的索引
topics, for the movie, and has some set of entries.
它包含了一些具体的项
And in this matrix notation,
在这个矩阵符号表示下
if you're familiar with matrix multiply, to get the entry.
假如你对矩阵乘法运算熟悉的话 就可以算出这个元素
So this is the uth row here, and the vth column here.
这是第u行 这是第v列
If we multiply these together, we get the uvth entry of this resulting matrix.
假如把它们乘在一起 可以得到结果矩阵的第uv个元素
So if you're not familiar with this kind of thing, that's okay.
如果你并不了解这类运算 也没关系
We're gonna talk about it in a lot more detail.
我们接下来会更详细的解释
In subsequent courses, but for those who are,
对于那些需要的同学们 随后有课程会详细讲解
this representation is a very compact way to take all of the vectors for
这是一种非常紧凑的方式 它可以表示出关于全部用户的所有向量
all of the users, so we're stacking up all of the user vectors,
这样 我们就获得许多用户向量
and stacking up all of the movie vectors.
还有许多电影向量
And through this representation,
并且 通过这种方式
we end up with an entire matrix which is just like we were writing before.
我们最终会得到一个完整的矩阵 就像之前写下的那种
It's a users by movies matrix.
是一个用户×电影的矩阵
So all of the users that appeared here [BLANK
所以 所有在这里的用户[写字声]
AUDIO] are appearing here, and all of the movies
都在这里了 并且所有的这里以列的形式表示出来的电影
that appeared as columns here are appearing as columns in this matrix.
都以这个矩阵里的每一列的方式表示出来了
And each individual entry, again, is a combination of a specific
再说一次 这里每一个单独的实体  都是这个矩阵的特定行L和特定列R的组合
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community